Jan Karon papers MSS 16077
University of Virginia, Special Collections Dept.
- Book manuscripts and related material
  - "Jeremy The Tale of an Honest Bunny," original notes, with Jan Karon's explanation about a note on the caption of an illustration that became the title to the second Mitford novel, 1986-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "Jeremy The Tale of an Honest Bunny," typed manuscript drafts, with letters from Elizabeth Law, Senior Editor, with her suggestions and revisions, 1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Jeremy The Tale of an Honest Bunny," typed manuscript drafts, with letters from Elizabeth Law, Senior Editor, with her suggestions and revisions, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Jeremy The Tale of an Honest Bunny," publicity and reviews, 1999-2000, 2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "Journey to Mitford" proposal from Dramatic Publishing Company, typescript of a play based on the Mitford novels by Jan Karon and adapted by Robert Inman, 2009; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Light from Heaven," author's notes and copy, [2005]; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "Light from Heaven," editorial correspondence, 2004-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "Light from Heaven," illustrations and cover art, 2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, chapters 1-7, copy edited manuscript, with changes and corrections, [2005 August 2]; 1 folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, chapters 8-14, copy edited manuscript, with changes and corrections, [2005 August 2]; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, chapters 15-21, and the afterward, copy edited manuscript, with changes and corrections, [2005 August 2]; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, chapters 1-7, with some changes and corrections, [2005 August]; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, chapters 8-15, with some changes and corrections, [2005 August]; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, chapters 16-21, and the afterward, with some changes and corrections, [2005 August]; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Light from Heaven," typed manuscript, new chapters 19 and 20, with revisions transferred to the copy edited set, [2005 August]; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Light from Heaven," chapter illustrations proofs and style sheet, 2005 August 9; 1 folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Light from Heaven," galley, first pass changes, 2005 August 15; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Light from Heaven," author's edited galley, first pass pages, 2005 August 15; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Light from Heaven," galley, first pass pages, with author's changes (1 of 3 folders), 2005 August 15; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "Light from Heaven," galley, first pass pages, with author's changes (2 of 3 folders), 2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Light from Heaven," galley, first pass pages, with author's changes (3 of 3 folders), 2005 August 15; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Light from Heaven," paperback, 2005-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "Light from Heaven," publicity, 2003, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "Light from Heaven," publicity - bestseller lists, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Light from Heaven," research, 1980-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Light from Heaven," research, 2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Light from Heaven," research, 2005 January-March; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Light from Heaven," research, 2005 April-July; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Light from Heaven," research, Undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "Light from Heaven," reviews, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - "A Light in the Window," author's notes, illustrations, and cover art, 1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "A Light in the Window," publicity, 1994-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," adapted for the stage, 2003-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," editorial correspondence, 1992-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," illustrations, 1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," typed manuscripts and audio script, including the unedited original typed manuscript and a Spanish translation, 1992-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," publicity and promotion, 1996-1999, 2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," publicity and promotion - flyers, catalog and packets, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," Puffin paperback edition, 2000-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," reader mail, 1997-2010; 1 folder(s) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," reader mail, including school classes, Undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Miss Fannie’s Hat," reviews, 1998-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "The Mitford Bedside Companion," editorial correspondence, 2002-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "The Mitford Bedside Companion," ideas and text, 1997-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "The Mitford Bedside Companion," illustrations and covers, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "The Mitford Bedside Companion," publicity and promotion, 2006-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "The Mitford Bedside Companion," working copy, formerly in a three ring binder, 2003 July; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - "The Mitford Snowmen," including the typed manuscript, proofs, illustrations, etc., 2000-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - "The Mitford Years" boxed set, including the copy, cover illustration, and design, 1997-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - "The Mitford Years" series, mass market promotion, 2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - "A New Song," correspondence concerning research, 1997-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "A New Song," cover art, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - "A New Song," editorial correspondence and style sheets, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "A New Song," illustrations, 1998-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "A New Song," original typed manuscript, chapters 1-4, [1998]; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "A New Song," original typed manuscript, chapters 5-9, [1998]; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "A New Song," original typed manuscript, chapters 10-15, [1998]; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "A New Song," copy edited typed manuscript, chapters 1-5, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "A New Song," copy edited typed manuscript, chapters 6-11, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - "A New Song," copy edited typed manuscript, chapters 12-17, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "A New Song," copy edited typed manuscript, chapters 18-22, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - "A New Song," interior design layouts, 1998 December 9; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - "A New Song," rough page proofs, with corrections and additions, 1999 January 11; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "A New Song," promotional materials, 1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "A New Song," research and notes, 1987-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "A New Song," research and notes, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "A New Song," research and notes, [1998]; 1 folder(s) (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - "Out to Canaan," author's notes and copy, 1994-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "Out to Canaan," cover art, illustrations and book casing, 1996-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "Out to Canaan," typed manuscript, chapters 1-6, 1997 January 28; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - "Out to Canaan," typed manuscript, chapters 7-12, 1997 January 28; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - "Out to Canaan," typed manuscript, chapters 13-17, 1997 January 28; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "Out to Canaan," typed manuscript, chapters 18-21, 1997 January 28; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "Out to Canaan," copy edited typed manuscript, pages 1-154, chapters 1-6, 1997 early February; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - "Out to Canaan," copy edited typed manuscript, pages 155-319, chapters 7-13, 1997 early February; 1 folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "Out to Canaan," copy edited typed manuscript, pages 320-471, chapters 14-21, 1997 early February; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Out to Canaan," page proofs, chapters 1-7, 1997 February 20; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Out to Canaan," page proofs, chapters 8-15, 1997 February 20; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - "Out to Canaan," page proofs, chapters 16-21, 1997 February 20; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "Out to Canaan," chapter illustration proofs, 1997 March 7; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Out to Canaan," research and notes, 1982, 1990-1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - "Out to Canaan," research and notes, 1997, 1990s; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Out to Canaan," reviews and promotional material, 1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "Patches of Godlight," editorial correspondence, 2000-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Patches of Godlight," copy edited typed manuscript, [2001]; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Patches of Godlight," covers and promotional material, 2001-2002 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," editorial and reader correspondence, 2002-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," illustrations and cover art, 2002-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," typed manuscript drafts, outline and chapters 1-6, [2003?]; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," copy edited typed manuscript, chapters 1-6, 2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," copy edited typed manuscript, chapters 7-10, 2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," author's rough pages, chapters 1-5, 2003 July 18; 1 folder(s) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," author's rough pages, chapters 6-10, 2003 July 18; 1 folder(s) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," research and notes, 1996, 2001-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "Shepherds Abiding," reviews and promotional material, 2002-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," notes and typed manuscript drafts of chapters 1-2, including chapter synopses, [2013?]; 1 folder(s) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," typed manuscript, spiral bound, unfinished draft read by Chris Pepe on her visit to Esmont, Virginia, 2013; 1 folder(s) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," typed manuscript, spiral bound, revised manuscript, second draft following input by Chris Pepe, 2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," copy edited galley, with changes and corrections, and with note "proofread March 26-April 16" (1 of 3 folders), 2014 March 25; 1 folder(s) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," copy edited galley, with changes and corrections, and with note "proofread March 26-April 16" (2 of 3 folders), 2014 March 25; 1 folder(s) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," copy edited galley, with changes and corrections, and with note "proofread March 26-April 16" (3 of 3 folders), 2014 March 25; 1 folder(s) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," galley proof, author's set, with date "March 26-April 9" added and a note to see queries with pages listed, both in red (1 of 3 folders), 2014 March 25; 1 folder(s) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," galley proof, author's set, with date "March 26-April 9" added and a note to see queries with pages listed, both in red (2 of 3 folders), 2014 March 25; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 1)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," galley proof, author's set, with date "March 26-April 9" added and a note to see queries with pages listed, both in red (3 of 3 folders), 2014 March 25; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 2)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," publicity - book tour schedule and bestseller lists, 2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 3)
  - "Somewhere Safe with Somebody Good," research, reviews, and promotional material, 2012-2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 4)
  - "These High Green Hills," chapter 1, a manuscript excerpt, and author's notes, 1994-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 5)
  - "These High Green Hills," illustrations and covers, 1995-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 6)
  - "These High Green Hills," publicity, 1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 25-A, Folder 7)
  - "The Trellis and the Seed," corrected page proofs (oversize), 2002 November 8; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 2)
  - "The Trellis and the Seed," editorial correspondence, 1993, 1999-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - "The Trellis and the Seed," illustrations and cover, 1998, 2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "The Trellis and the Seed," typed manuscripts and proofs, 1999, 2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "Violet Comes to Stay," editorial file, 2000-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "Violet Comes to Stay," illustrations, with interior sketches and bookjacket, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "Violet Comes to Stay," typed manuscripts by Melanie Cecka, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Violet Comes to Stay," marketing plan and publicity, 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Violet Comes to Stay," sales samples and sell-in brochure, 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "Violet Comes to Stay," illustrations, including cover designs and layouts, color copies of the interior art, and a cover composition, some annotated by Jan Karon with suggestions and corrections (oversize), 2005-2006; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 3)
  - "Violet Goes to the Country," editorial file, 2006-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Violet Goes to the Country," typed manuscripts by Melanie Cecka, 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - "Violet Goes to the Country," sketches by Emily Arnold McCully, annotated by Jan Karon on September 10, 2006 (oversize), 2006 September 7; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 4)
  - "Violet Goes to the Country," artwork by Emily Arnold McCully and flap copy (oversize), 2006 December 11; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 5)
  - "Violet Goes to the Country," preliminary page proofs with book jacket, includes a letter from Viking editor, Joy Peskin, and a copy of a proposed ad for Parade Magazine, August 21, 2007 (oversize), 2007 February 1; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 6)
  - "Violet Goes to the Country," page proofs with book jacket (oversize), 2007 February 28; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 1)
- Reader mail, Series II
  - Reader Mail, 1994-1996 May; Box 27; 11 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1996 June-December; Box 28; 8 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, [1996]-1997 May; Box 29; 8 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1997 May-August; Box 30; 7 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1997 August-November; Box 31; 8 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1997 December-1998 January; Box 32; 7 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1998 January-February; Box 33; 6 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1998 March-April; Box 34; 8 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1998 May-June; Box 35; 6 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1998 June-August; Box 36; 7 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1998 August-October; Box 37; 7 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1998 October-[1998]; Box 38; 8 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1999 January-March; Box 39; 8 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1999 April-May; Box 40; 7 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 1999 May-October; Box 41; 7 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, [1999]-[2005]; Box 42; 12 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail, 2006-2016; Box 43; 11 folder(s)
  - Reader Mail – Gift of artwork featuring Jesus with children and a quote from the children’s song Jesus Loves Me made by a fan, 2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Reader Mail – Directions for a Mitford computer game based on the computer game Mah Jongg, developed by Jamie D. Wilson, Zebulon, North Carolina and sent with a letter, February 17, 1998, to Jan Karon; For actual game see: Disk 2473-000, 1 folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Reader Mail – Gift of a cross stitch by fan, Dixie Bishop, “Philippians 4:13 for Pete’s sake” signed by participants in the Second International Mitford Homecoming, Blowing Rock, North Carolina (oversize), 2007; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 2)
  - Reader Mail – Gifts sent to Jan Karon, including poster commemorating the 3rd International Mitford Homecoming; Merry Christmas artwork, signed by readers; a watercolor of Jan Karon; and a photograph of a painting of Mitford by a reader, Marlynne Snare (oversize), 1998-2009; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 3)
- Professional correspondence and papers, Series III
  - Addresses and Talks by Jan Karon, 1995-2010; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Addresses and Talks by Jan Karon, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Addresses and Talks by Jan Karon, research material, 1993-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Augsburg Fortress Publishers, 1996-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Recognitions, 1994-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Awards and Recognitions, 1998-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Awards and Recognitions – Library of Virginia Lifetime Achievement Award and Literary Luncheon, 2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Book numbers or printings, 1995-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Bookstores, 1989-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Bookstores, 1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Bookstores, 1997-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - "Charlotte" – Articles by Jan Karon, 1977; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - "A Common Reader", 1995-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Cook Classic Series, includes introductions and reader’s guides by Dale Brown, Professor of English, Calvin College, for "At Home in Mitford," "A Light in the Window," and "These High Green Hills", 2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Di Novi Pictures, including a few other offers from producers to do a Mitford film, 1994-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Di Novi Pictures, including a few other offers from producers to do a Mitford film, 2005-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Di Novi Pictures – "At Home in Mitford," changes discussed with Ann Hamilton, 2001 February; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Easton Press, 2003-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - G.P. Putnam’s Sons, 2012-2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - G.P. Putnam’s Sons, 2015 January-September; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - G.P. Putnam’s Sons, 2015 October-2016 March; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Guideposts Books, 1995-1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Hallmark, 1997-1998 April; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Hallmark, 1998 May-December; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Hallmark, 1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Hallmark, 2000-2001, 2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Hallmark - contracts, 1997-2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Hallmark - Information Packets, 1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Hallmark - Mitford Greeting Cards (Examples), [1998?]; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, 1998 February-April; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, 1998 May; 1 folder(s) (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, 1998 August-October; 1 folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, 1998 November; 1 folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, 1998 December; 1 folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, [1998]; 1 folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, [1998]; 1 folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs, 1999-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Hallmark – Products and Designs - Mitford Snowmen, [1999]; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Hallmark - Royalties, 1999-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Ideas for Articles, 1977-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Ideas for Characters, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Ideas for Children's Books, 1989-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Interviews of Jan Karon, 1997-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 6)
    Interviews can also be found in publicity files.
  - Lion Publishing, Illinois, 1993; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Lion Publishing, Illinois, 1994 January-August; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Lion Publishing, Illinois, 1994 September-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Lion Publishing, Illinois, 1996-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Lion Publishing, Illinois - Contracts, 1993-1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Lion Publishing, Illinois - Promotional Material, 1994-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Lion Publishing PLC, United Kingdom, 1994-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Lion Publishing PLC, United Kingdom, 1996-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Literary Agents, 1989-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Agents include the Jeanne Drewsen Agency and Jennie Dunham. This folder is significant because it predates the Mitford series taking off and contains the advice of various editors and Jan’s own musing about what to do.
  - Literary Agents – Liz Darhansoff, 1994-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 3)
    These files chart the progress of the relationship between Jan Karon and her agent, from the beginning when Nancy Olson, Quail Ridge Books, Raleigh, North Carolina, referred Karon to Darhansoff (December 15, 1994 and January 18, 1995) and reveal many details about her literary career, including the transition from Lion Publishing to Penguin.
  - Literary Agents – Liz Darhansoff, 1998-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Literary Agents – Liz Darhansoff, 2000-2013; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 5)
    This file includes a proposal for Father Tim and Cynthia mysteries and a discussion of the publication of a journal.
  - Penguin Audiobooks, 1996-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Penguin Books Great Ideas Series covers from the first set, circa 2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Penguin Books 75th Anniversary, 2010; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Penguin – United Kingdom and Canada, 1997-2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Penguin Website, 1997-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Permission Requests, 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Philomel Books concerning "Miss Fannie’s Hat", 1993-1994; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Poetry by Jan Karon, [1979?], 2013; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Promotional Material, circa 1998-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events, 1995-1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events, 1997 January-April; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events, 1997 May-December; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events - The Muses proudly presents author Jan Karon autographing "Out to Canaan" and the Mitford Mayoral Election, 1997 May 18; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events – Mitford Fashion Show to Benefit the Blowing Rock Hospital, held on August 8, 1997, 1996-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events, 1998 January-April; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events, 1998 May-December; 1 folder(s) (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events (1 of 2 folders), 1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Public Appearances and Author Events (2 of 2 folders), 1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 51, Folder 2)